Refer to More On Modules.py for programs and python 3.7 documentation for tutorial.

MODULES-
If you quit from the Python interpreter and enter it again, the deﬁnitions you have made (functions and variables) are lost. Therefore, if you want to write a somewhat longer program, you are better off using a text editor to prepare the input for the interpreter and running it with that ﬁle as input instead. This is known as creating a script. As your program gets longer, you may want to split it into several ﬁles for easier maintenance. You may also want to use a handy function that you’ve written in several programs without copying its deﬁnition into each program. 

To support this, Python has a way to put deﬁnitions in a ﬁle and use them in a script or in an interactive instance of the interpreter. Such a ﬁle is called a module; deﬁnitions from a module can be imported into other modules or into the main module(the collection of variables that you have access to in a script executed at the top level and in calculator mode). 
Module is a file containing Python definitions and statements. File name is itself referred to as module name with .py extension, this extension is automatically appended to the file name while saving it as Python file. Within a module, the module's name (as a string) is available as the value of the global variable __name__. In other words, global variable __name__ == module's name, within a module. We can also say that __name__ is assigned module's name. 
Write a file named FibonacciReturn.py and save it, this file has definitions and  statements for printing fibonacci series lesser than or equal to num passed as an argument while calling or accessing that specific function. Later, we use import keyword to import same file on shell or in our program to use it's functionalities without actually writing or including the definitions or statements but importing or including the file as a whole. We can also access different functions of that module through module name.
Ex-
def fib(n): # write Fibonacci series up to n
	a, b = 0, 1
	while b < n:
		print(b, end=' ') 
		a, b = b, a+b 
	print()
def fib2(n): # return Fibonacci series up to n
	result = []
	a, b = 0, 1 
	while b < n:
		result.append(b)
		a, b = b, a+b
	return result 
Now enter the Python interpreter and import this module with the following command:
>>> import fibo
This does not enter the names of the functions defined in fibo directly in the current symbol table; it only enters the module name fibo there. Using the module name you can access the functions:
>>> fibo.fib(1000)
0 1 1 2 3 5 8 13 21 34 55 89 144 233 377 610 987
>>> fibo.fib2(100)
[0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34, 55, 89]
>>> fibo.__name__
'fibo'
# We access fib() and fib2() functions through
module name,i.e, fibo.
If you intend to use a function often you can assign it to a local name:
>>> fib = fibo.fib
>>> fib(500)
0 1 1 2 3 5 8 13 21 34 55 89 144 233 377

MORE ON MODULES -
A module can contain executable statements and function definitions. These statements are intended to initialize the module. They are executed only the first time the module name is encountered in an import statement.(They are also run if the file is executed as a script.)
Each module has its own private symbol table, which is used as the global symbol table by all functions defined in the module. Thus, the author of a module can use global variables in the module without worrying about accidental clashes with a user’s global variables. On the other hand, if you know what you are doing you can touch a module’s global variables with the same notation used to refer to its functions, modname.itemname.
Modules can import other modules. Customary(convention) but not required to place all 'import' statements at the beginning of a module(or script, when used). Whenever, we write or include import statement or import a module, the imported module names are placed in the (current) importing module's global symbol table.
There are two ways to import a module-
1. import complete module by using import statement, the imported module name will be placed into the importing module's global symbol table.
2. from "imported module name" import "function names" :
This statement directly places the imported module names into the importing module's private symbol table(or global symbol table for functions defined within importing module). This statement doesn't include or define imported module's name(fibo or FibonacciReturn) into importing module's symbol table. It simply defines the functions which are imported from the imported(not actually imported but foreign) module into importing module. 
To import all names of a module we can write:
syntax: from "module name" import *
Ex- from FibonacciReturn import fibonacci_return
This imports all names except those beginning with an underscore (_). In most cases Python programmers do not use this facility since it introduces an unknown set of names into the interpreter, possibly hiding some things you have already deﬁned. 
Note that in general the practice of importing * from a module or package is frowned upon(disapproved), since it often causes poorly readable code. However, it is okay to use it to save typing in interactive sessions. 
If the module name is followed by 'as', then the name following as is bound directly to the imported module. 
>>> import fibo as fib 
>>> fib.fib(500) 
0 1 1 2 3 5 8 13 21 34 55 89 144 233 377
For efficiency reasons, each module is only imported once per interpreter session. Therefore, if you change your modules, you must restart the interpreter – or, if it’s just one module you want to test interactively, use importlib.reload(), e.g. import importlib; importlib.reload(modulename).
